Now, let's see how we can use
下面看看如何利用
the Fama French three-factor model to fill in the values we need for the risk model.
Fama French 三因子模型填充风险模型的值
We have three factors,
我们有三个因子
so we'll fill in the covariance matrix of factors that is three by three.
所以因子协方差矩阵是 3x3
Notice that the first row has the market factor in all three columns,
注意 第一行的三列都是市场因子
the second row has the size factor,
第二行是市值因子
and the third row has the value factor.
第三行是价值因子
We want time series of three factor returns;
我们希望获得市场 市值和价值
market, size, and value.
这三个因子收益率的时间序列
The market factor can be the excess return of a market index such as the S&amp;P 500.
市场因子可以是市场指数（例如 S&amp;P 500）的超额收益率
The size factor is the return of a theoretical portfolio that long,
市值因子等于做多小盘股并做空大盘股的
small stocks and shorts, big stocks.
理论投资组合的收益率
So, it's going along the three small portfolios and shorting the three big portfolios.
它将做多三个小盘股投资组合并做空三个大盘股投资组合
The value factor is the return of
价值因子等于
the theoretical portfolio that longs value stocks and shorts growth stocks.
做多价值股并做空增长股的理论投资组合的收益率
So, it's going long two value portfolios and shorting two growth portfolios.
它将做多两个价值股投资组合并做空两个增长股投资组合
You can pause here to study these formulas before continuing.
你可以暂停视频并仔细研究下这些公式 然后继续观看
Now, let's look at the matrix of factor exposures.
现在看看因子暴露度矩阵
We'll assume just two stocks.
假设有两支股票
Each stock has a factor exposure for each of the three factors.
每支股票对三个因子中的每个都有一个因子暴露度
The transpose of the factor exposure matrix looks similar,
因子暴露度矩阵的转置矩阵看起来相似
just turned on its side.
只是翻转过来了
To estimate factor exposures for the first stock,
我们可以通过回归
we can use regression,
估算第一支股票的因子暴露度
this time a multiple regression.
这次使用多元回归
For the first stock,
对于第一支股票
the regression looks like this.
回归是这样的
The independent variables are the factor returns for the market, size, and value.
自变量是市场、市值和价值的因子收益率
The dependent variable is the return of the first stock.
因变量是第一支股票的收益率
The same procedure can be used to estimate the factor exposure for stock two.
然后按照相同的流程估算第二支股票的因子暴露度
The specific variance matrix holds the variance for
特有方差矩阵包含了
each stock that is not attributable to these factors.
每支股票中这些因子无法解释的方差
For the specific variants of the first stock,
对于第一支股票的特有方差
let's first get a time series of the specific return.
我们先获得特有收益率的时间序列
The specific return for each day is
每天的特有收益率
the actual return of the stock minus is estimated return.
等于股票的实际收益率减去估算收益率
The estimated return is calculated using
我们可以使用之前计算的
the factor returns and factor exposures that we calculated earlier.
因子收益率和因子暴露度计算估算收益率
We can do the same for the second stock.
第二支股票的流程一样
Taking the variance of the specific returns gives us
计算特有收益率的方差
the values that we can put in the matrix of specific variances.
可以获得能填充到特有方差矩阵中的值
You can pause here to study the formulas a bit.
你可以暂停视频并仔细研究下这些公式
So, we did it. We have all the pieces that go into the factor model of
我们做到了我们获得了填充投资组合方差因子模型
portfolio variance and we estimated
所有部分的值
these values using the Fama French three-factor model.
并且使用 Fama French 三因子模型估算出这些值
Just a reminder that this approach is called a Time Series Risk Model.
注意 这个方法叫做时间序列风险模型
Next, we'll look at another common type of risk model,
接下来我们将了解另一种常见的风险模型
which is the cross-sectional risk model.
叫做横截面风险模型